<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Walter Manger</title><link>https://wmanger.com/</link><description>Recent content on Walter Manger</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wmanger.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://wmanger.com/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/about/</guid><description>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Walter Manger.
If you were coming here to read about my professional experience, you should consider visiting my linkedin profile for that. This site features opinionated articles about the software industry, business in general, and mindset, with some form of technical focus.
If you need help with Cloud Migration, Cloud Infrastructure, Serverless Applications, Software Roadmapping, email me.
You can get more information about the services that I offer on the services page.</description></item><item><title>2022 In Review</title><link>https://wmanger.com/articles/2022-in-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/articles/2022-in-review/</guid><description>Figure 1: Photo by Markus Winkler via Pexels
It 2022, I:
Took a new position I&amp;rsquo;m working in an industry that I have not been exposed to (Ad Tech), using a language that I haven&amp;rsquo;t written for a while (Golang), embracing some techniques and technologies I have not used in a professional context (Bazel, Tilt, Monorepo).
Traveled At the end of the school year, we got to visit Yellowstone National Park just before it got flooded out.</description></item><item><title>DIY Free Static Blog Publishing Platform</title><link>https://wmanger.com/articles/free-diy-static-site-publisher/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/articles/free-diy-static-site-publisher/</guid><description>Preview of the DIY Publishing Platform
This site is generated by a static site generator (SSG) called hugo , but this guide will work with any SSG.
Motivation I wanted to be able to keep raw markdown, and any other files that may be considered private, separate from what is viewable by the public.
Parts A private Github repository to contain your raw markdown and any other assets that may or may not be considered publishable.</description></item><item><title>Golang on Doom Emacs</title><link>https://wmanger.com/articles/go-on-doom-emacs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/articles/go-on-doom-emacs/</guid><description>Photo by Patrice Schoefolt from Pexels
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve contributed to any Golang , but I got the itch this weekend to setup my Doom Emacs to do so.
Most of the time I don&amp;rsquo;t want a full-blown IDE experience as having all the bells and whistles of that type of environment can be distracting. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;d like to turn on features as I need them.</description></item><item><title>The Sugar Brain Fix</title><link>https://wmanger.com/book-notes/the-sugar-brain-fix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 23:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/book-notes/the-sugar-brain-fix/</guid><description>&lt;p>This book has an interesting position on how the brain treats bad foods. In a nutshell, the reason why we reach for bad foods is the result of being deficient in Dopamine and Serotonin, which these bad foods trick the brain into releasing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Supporting Multiple Git/Github Accounts</title><link>https://wmanger.com/articles/supporting-multiple-github-accounts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/articles/supporting-multiple-github-accounts/</guid><description>Photo by Marcin Szmigiel from Pexels
Many times, especially when working as a freelance developer, you&amp;rsquo;ll need access to multiple Github repositories. Most likely, you will be using different Github accounts, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need to tell git which account to use. To do this, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to configure your ~/.ssh/config and ~/.gitconfig accordingly.
I won&amp;rsquo;t go into great detail in this post, as there already is really good documentation here on how to configure ssh for Github.</description></item><item><title>On becoming a Certified Kubernetes Application Developer</title><link>https://wmanger.com/articles/on-becoming-a-ckad/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/articles/on-becoming-a-ckad/</guid><description>Over the past few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been head-down on learning more about Kubernetes. To help solidify this learning, I thought that it would be a good idea to add some icing on the cake and attempt the CKAD exam.
I am glad to report that as of today, I am a Certified Kubernetes Application Developer.
My study strategy wasn&amp;rsquo;t really unique, but I&amp;rsquo;ll describe it below.
Don&amp;rsquo;t Waste Time Don&amp;rsquo;t waste time wondering how long it takes or how much effort it takes to be ready for the exam.</description></item><item><title>The Pragmatic Programmer</title><link>https://wmanger.com/book-notes/revisiting-the-pragmatic-programmer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 23:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/book-notes/revisiting-the-pragmatic-programmer/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is probably one of the most classic programming books that is frequently recommended to programmers by programmers.
I catagorize this type of book as &lt;em>Programmer&amp;rsquo;s Self-Help&lt;/em>.
Some will find it helpful, others look for more actionable advice.
I read this when I was about 2 years into my software engineering career.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Home</title><link>https://wmanger.com/home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/home/</guid><description>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Walter Manger.
If you were coming here to read about my professional experience, you should consider visiting my linkedin profile for that. This site features opinionated articles about the software industry, business in general, and mindset, with some form of technical focus.
If you need help with Cloud Migration, Cloud Infrastructure, Serverless Applications, Software Roadmapping, email me.
You can get more information about the services that I offer on the services page.</description></item><item><title>How To Know</title><link>https://wmanger.com/articles/how-to-know/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/articles/how-to-know/</guid><description>References https://www.lesswrong.com/tag/bayesianism
https://www.lesswrong.com/tag/rationalist-movement
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roe_v._Wade
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abortion_in_Texas#:~:text=A%20law%20passed%20in%201992,or%20indirectly%20in%20the%20procedure
https://www.constituteproject.org/constitution/United_States_of_America_1992
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abortion_statistics_in_the_United_States
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abortion_in_Portugal
https://abortion.procon.org/
What is it? How many are done a year and by who? How to Think Arguments It&amp;#39;s just a clump of cells https://www.liveaction.org/news/respond-pro-abortion-clump-of-cells-argument/
It is murder Religious argument, but on the contrary, free will.</description></item><item><title>Services</title><link>https://wmanger.com/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/services/</guid><description>Services to help your business harness the cloud confidently.
One Hour Cloud Strategy Call Making sure that Cloud Infrastructure is right for your project and organization is key.
Do you have questions about how Serverless technologies can reduce costs and increase resilience? Need suggestions about how your CI/CD pipeline could serve you better? Are you in the cloud, but making a decision between using a managed service or hosting one?</description></item><item><title>Tools</title><link>https://wmanger.com/my-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmanger.com/my-tools/</guid><description>I decided instead of just a raw, bulleted list, I&amp;rsquo;d mimic the format of usesthis.com to describe the tools that I use frequently.
What hardware do i use? I use a MacBook Pro (Retina, 15-inch, Mid 2015) - 2.2 Quad Core Processor, 16GB memory, 250GB SSD.
My 2015 G&amp;amp;L Legacy Special guitar is my daily driver these days. I play it through a Marshall Origin 20, but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with using only a HX Stomp.</description></item></channel></rss>