<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oss on To The Triforce</title>
    <link>http://wmanger.com/tags/oss/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oss on To The Triforce</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://wmanger.com/tags/oss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Linux Mint &amp; CLI Wonderment</title>
      <link>http://wmanger.com/post/2017-03-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 11:24:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wmanger.com/post/2017-03-07/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I decided to install Linux Mint 18 on my old laptop. I really wanted to know what it was like to have a Linux as a primary OS. Initially, I installed a Linux on a VM and having it there was handy, but I found myself not opening the VM. With it installed as my primary OS, I am forced into using it. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been really curious about Linux and how to harness the power &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s just hard to commit to learning a particular OS when it is not your primary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tlcl-ftw&#34;&gt;TLCL FTW&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before I took the plunge, I picked up a physical copy of &lt;em&gt;The Linux Command Line&lt;/em&gt; from the local library (it is now late). There is so much great information in that book. You learn little things about the built-in utilities and now basically the OS is an IDE. In the first chapter, the author writes about a scenario where two developers (C++ vs Bash) looking at the same problem solved it in very different ways. Spoiler alert: the Bash approach was orders of magnitude less code. This was the main draw to learning more about Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I can get around Linux pretty well. I just wanted to dig more into the utilities that are available to become more efficient on the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dangerous-thoughts&#34;&gt;Dangerous Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had pretty good success getting my development environment up and running on Linux. I even scripted out some of the configuration so it can be replicated on other Debian based systems. At this point, I don&amp;rsquo;t see a reason to go elsewhere. In fact, I like this environment so much, I &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; want to go elsewhere. That&amp;rsquo;s the dangerous thing. I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought that one should be as OS agnostic as possible, but I think when you get exposed to the powerful tools that live in Linux, going outside this environment is difficult. I know that OSX and now Windows 10 have proper support for Bash, but it is here now and it is free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-audio-other-things&#34;&gt;What About Audio &amp;amp; Other Things?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is something I am working to try to get to parity with. Currently, OSX and Windows have great support for Audio applications. Not to mention, the VSTs that I&amp;rsquo;ve recently used are so much better than they used to be. I am not opposed to maybe dual-booting for that particular need. We&amp;rsquo;ll see what comes from my digging.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>