<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogging on To The Triforce</title>
    <link>http://wmanger.com/tags/blogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogging on To The Triforce</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 14:57:47 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wmanger.com/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning Again, statically</title>
      <link>http://wmanger.com/post/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 14:57:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wmanger.com/post/first/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start writing blog posts again since I am learning new things and I&amp;rsquo;d like to document the things I am learning in an attempt to measure progress. With this, a few things have changed. My original blog engine was blogger (very neglected), but I have recently started using &lt;a href=&#34;http://emacsformacosx.com/&#34;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; and, really, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave Emacs. I know there are modes for posting to blogger, but since I am starting to hack Golang, I think using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;static blogging engine written in Go&lt;/a&gt; is appropriate. I don&amp;rsquo;t know of any special functions or modes to make using Hugo easier for the Emacs user, so there is room for me to learn how to make these functions/modes myself. Benefits galore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why:e8fb9c67eba912c72729806db31eaa1b&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a long story, but I am trying out Sacha&amp;rsquo;s method of learning things. Along with her &lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.sachachua.com/sharing/blog.html#value-blogging&#34;&gt;articles on blogging for learning&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve read others who use the same technique for an efficient learning environment. I have many things that I am learning all at once and I need a way to organize and solidify my learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-ll-post:e8fb9c67eba912c72729806db31eaa1b&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ll Post&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, the posts on this blog will mostly relate to programming &amp;ndash; ranging from slightly technical to overly technical. Overly technical posts will have little commentary and mostly code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-i-ll-post:e8fb9c67eba912c72729806db31eaa1b&#34;&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;ll Post&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no intended schedule and I cannot promise that posts will happen on a regular basis. I will try one post a week. That seems reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goodbye-for-now:e8fb9c67eba912c72729806db31eaa1b&#34;&gt;Goodbye for now&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goodbye, until the next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>